<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Priydarshi Singh</title>
    <link>https://dryairship.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Priydarshi Singh</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Priydarshi Singh {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 23:00:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://dryairship.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Google FooBar Experience</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-google-foobar-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 23:00:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-google-foobar-experience/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hey all! This blog post is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://foobar.withgoogle.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google FooBar&lt;/a&gt;, how I got invited to it, the problems, and what happened at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;invitation&#34;&gt;Invitation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legend has it that Google FooBar is Google’s &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;secret hiring challenge&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. You can take part in it only if you have an invitation and you if you perform well enough you may be hired! I am aware of two ways one can get an invitation :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Search -&lt;/strong&gt; Apparently, making enough programming related searches on Google can get you an invitation (as was the case with me). I have no idea regarding the algorithm which decides if you have made &lt;em&gt;enough&lt;/em&gt; searches. I have been searching for solutions to programming problems since 2012 (okay, those searches must have been quite silly), and it was only in January 2017 that I got the invitation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referral -&lt;/strong&gt; People who have completed some challenges on FooBar get a URL which they can share with their friends to invite them to participate. Again, I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many challenges one needs to solve to get the referral link. I got mine when FooBar resumed after being down for extended maintenance for about a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interface&#34;&gt;Interface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After logging in, one is greeted with a linux-terminal like screen. &lt;code&gt;help&lt;/code&gt; lists out the various commands that work in this terminal.
&lt;img src=&#34;commands.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google FooBar Commands&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;request&lt;/code&gt; creates a new directory which contains the problem statement and the solution templates. The solutions can be in either &lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;python&lt;/strong&gt;. One can only have a single active challenge at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time I was invited for the challenge, Java was, sort-of, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/search?tab=votes&amp;amp;q=user%3a4121347%20%5bjava%5d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my mother tongue&lt;/a&gt; :p. So I submitted my solutions in Java. The Java template for each problem had a function like this, which we were supposed to complete :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Java&#34;&gt;public static int answer(&amp;lt;params&amp;gt;) {
    ...
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;problems&#34;&gt;Problems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems were like regular &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Competitive_programming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CP&lt;/a&gt; problems. Most of them were solvable by using &lt;strong&gt;dynamic programming&lt;/strong&gt;. However, at that time, I was a novice at CP and completely inexperienced at dynamic programming, and hence solving every problem was a matter of extreme pride and happiness for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems were divided into 5 levels :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 1 had 1 problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 2 had 2 problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 3 had 3 problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 4 again had 2 problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 5 supposedly had only 1 problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to sail through the first four levels easily (except problem 2 of level 3 - to be explained in a later blog post), but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t complete the challenge as I failed to solve the only problem of the 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had 25 days to solve the last problem, and I spent the first 10 days without much worry - I was doltishly expecting this one to be of the same difficulty level as the previous ones, which were surprisingly quite simple. As it turned out, I was very wrong. I came up with a few different ways to solve the problem, but all my solutions were essentially brute-force (with a time complexity  of O(2&lt;sup&gt;mn&lt;/sup&gt;)) and were naturally taking a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I lost all hopes of solving the problem on my own, I posted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/q/41923054/4121347&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;question on StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;, and even put a bounty on it! However, I failed to get an answer (the question has no accepted answer even today, because apparently the problem was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cellular_automaton&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cellular Automation&lt;/a&gt; problem, and my naive approach was very different from the expected solution).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;status&lt;/code&gt; commands prints the progress of a user. For me, the output is like this :
&lt;img src=&#34;status.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google FooBar Status&#34; /&gt;
When I cleared the third level, Google gave me an option to use the &lt;code&gt;recruitme&lt;/code&gt; command, which supposedly shared my progress with a Google recruiter. I decided to use it at the end of the challenge. Later, since I couldn&amp;rsquo;t solve the last problem, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really expect anyone from Google to contact me. Still, hoping for the best, I used the command, and entered the information it asked - like name, contact details, education etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard from any Google recruiter. Perhaps because I was still in school then - they asked this when I entered the details. Or maybe because I cheated on the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; problem of the 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; level (read the next blog post for details). Or perhaps because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t solve the last problem. Or maybe because Google stopped hiring through FooBar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reason may be, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really disappointed. Solving those problems gave me immense confidence and the inspiration to perform better at the next opportunity I get. And of course, the invitation for Google FooBar is in itself a procurement to cherish!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meow, World!</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/meow-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 23:33:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/meow-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there, everyone! I am Priydarshi and this is my blog. Here I would be posting primarily programming related stuff, in addition to my experiences at IITK and in general life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the motivation for me to start this blog?&lt;br /&gt;
1. Almost all of the cool seniors I know have their own blogs.&lt;br /&gt;
2. I believe I have stories to tell, and knowledge to share.&lt;br /&gt;
3. I wanted to tick off another item from my bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final examinations for the second semester ended yesterday and so now I finally have the time to try my hand at maintaining a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently this blog is hosted on GitHub Pages (&lt;em&gt;though I might later shift it to a personal domain&lt;/em&gt;). I am using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt; theme and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; framework for maintaining this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Hugo claims to be user-friendly, my experience with setting up this blog wasn&amp;rsquo;t as smooth as I expected it to be. So I find &lt;code&gt;apt&lt;/code&gt; to be easiest way to install any package. But apparently, &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install hugo&lt;/code&gt; installs an older version of Hugo, and on trying to build this site with that version, I ended up with an error message telling me that the Academic theme isn&amp;rsquo;t compatible with my current Hugo version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Current theme does not support Hugo version 0.40.1. Minimum version required is 0.54
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I purged the &lt;code&gt;apt&lt;/code&gt; version. What, then, is the next easiest way to install a package? &lt;code&gt;snap&lt;/code&gt;! So I did &lt;code&gt;sudo snap install hugo&lt;/code&gt;. Trying to build the site with this gave me another scary error message :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;failed to transform resource: TOCSS: failed to transform &amp;quot;scss/main.scss&amp;quot; (text/x-scss): this feature is not available in your current Hugo version, see https://goo.gl/YMrWcn for more information.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some unknown reason, I chose to ignore the link in the error message and decided to Google the error. I found the same error on StackOverflow (&lt;em&gt;The real happiness? +_+&lt;/em&gt;) and the accepted answer recommended me to install the tarball version of Hugo. So I did that, but ended up with the same error message. (&lt;em&gt;What can be more sad than an accepted SO answer not helping you out?&lt;/em&gt; ;_; )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I decided to follow the link in the error message, and found a very easy &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/troubleshooting/faq/#i-get-tocss-this-feature-is-not-available-in-your-current-hugo-version&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;solution&lt;/a&gt; to this error - apparently I had installed the normal version, whereas I needed the &lt;code&gt;extended&lt;/code&gt; version. (&lt;em&gt;*facepalm*&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learnt : &lt;strong&gt;An error message doesn&amp;rsquo;t always come with a link to its solution. So when it does, follow the link blindly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my first blog post. Hope you stick around to read my future posts!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Election Manager</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/project/online-election-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 19:32:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/project/online-election-manager/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
