<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Priydarshi Singh</title>
    <link>https://dryairship.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Priydarshi Singh</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Priydarshi Singh {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 04:27:10 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://dryairship.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Rust Program</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-first-rust-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 04:27:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-first-rust-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rust has been declared as the most loved programming language consecutively for the past four years in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2019#most-loved-dreaded-and-wanted&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;StackOverflow Developer Survey&lt;/a&gt;. I myself marked Rust as one of the languages I&amp;rsquo;d like to work with in the future, in the 2020 Survey. And due to the COVID-19 vacations, I finally got the time to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I installed Rust and read a few pages of &lt;a href=&#34;https://doc.rust-lang.org/rust-by-example/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rust by Example&lt;/a&gt;. Then I came across this problem about &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.tanyakhovanova.com/2020/03/a-game-with-the-devil/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a game of coins with the Devil&lt;/a&gt;, and decided to implement the game as my first project in Rust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in learning languages the hard way. I learnt Java by experimenting. I used to copy code that I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand, then modified small parts, observed the changes, and repeated this until I understood the entire code. And I learnt python and C++ by by using them to re-write the same programs that I wrote in Java. This also taught me how to use Google properly. I learnt Go by deciding that I&amp;rsquo;d use it to build my best self project yet (an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dryairship/online-election-manager&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;online election system&lt;/a&gt;), when I hardly knew how to write Hello World in it; and I learnt it not by following some guide, but by searching for &amp;ldquo;how to do X in Go&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why should Rust be an exception? I created a new cargo project and started modifying it. I really liked that creating a new project is as simple as doing &lt;code&gt;cargo new project-name&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I had to do was to take an integer as an input. I was awfully disappointed that there is no direct way to take an integer input: we first have to input a string and then parse it into an integer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java, at one point, used to be my favourite language. And Java libraries use the camelCase/PascalCase for all naming purposes (except for CONSTANTS). Now Go is my favourite language. And Go too uses a similar convention. Therefore, all my life, I&amp;rsquo;ve preferred using the camelCase. And now I&amp;rsquo;m writing code in a language that gives me a warning, asking me to convert camelCase variable names to snake_case. First turn-off. :p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the input part was ready, I ran it using &lt;code&gt;cargo run&lt;/code&gt;. It seemed to take infinity to compile - when I realized that it was in fact waiting for the input. However, I had &lt;code&gt;print!&lt;/code&gt;ed a string before asking for the input, which was not displayed. Flushing problem, I recognized. Changing &lt;code&gt;print!&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;println!&lt;/code&gt; did the work, but I still wanted the input to be taken on the same line as the prompt. So I had to add another statement to flush - a rather scary looking statement that required a new Trait to be imported. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like having to manually flush after &lt;code&gt;print!&lt;/code&gt;ing, but there has been a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/23818&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;huge discussion over this&lt;/a&gt; and the community believes this is the way it should be. :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next step, I had to create an array of the size that I had just inputted. The error messages told me that I could not use a variable for the size of the array - it had to be a constant. LoL what? I then found that the way to do it is by using a vector. Fair enough. Then I realized that an &lt;code&gt;i32&lt;/code&gt; value could not be used as an array/vector index; it had to be a &lt;code&gt;usize&lt;/code&gt;.  Reasonable, since array indices should be positive. However, I believe an automatic type conversion should have been implemented (again, the subject of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/29010&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a huge discussion&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then had to randomly initialize the vector. Turns out, I have to add an &lt;strong&gt;external crate&lt;/strong&gt; as a dependency to generate random numbers. Seriously? In my opinion, random number generation is something as fundamental as I/O and should have been present in the standard library of Rust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I had a randomly initialized array. I now needed to update it using inputs from the user. I was about to face the most dreaded error any Rust beginner could face : &lt;code&gt;error[E0382]: use of moved value&lt;/code&gt;. The concept of this error doesn&amp;rsquo;t even exist in other languages. &lt;em&gt;So I modified the vector in an iteration of the while loop and now I can&amp;rsquo;t use the vector in the while condition? LMAO why?&lt;/em&gt; It took me an entire day to figure it out, and I have probably not yet properly understood it. I somehow managed to solve it, but I still don&amp;rsquo;t know if the way I did it is the way it was supposed to be done. I&amp;rsquo;ll need to understand the idea of ownership before I pick up any other project in Rust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was it - an utterly disappointing experience. I once overheard &lt;a href=&#34;https://yashsriv.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;yashsriv&lt;/a&gt; saying that anyone denigrating Rust online would be hurled abuses at. So perhaps I should brace for that. The program is available on GitHub at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dryairship/coins-and-the-devil&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dryairship/coins-and-the-devil&lt;/a&gt;. Do point out any mistakes by creating a GitHub issue or in the comments here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Guess Might Not Be as Good as Mine!</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/your-guess-might-not-be-as-good-as-mine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 06:59:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/your-guess-might-not-be-as-good-as-mine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was in a discussion with my friend Avinandan Bose once. He had just returned from the mid-semester examination of an MTH course. The subject of our concern was the format of the examination - a rather unusual one for such a consequential test. The test had 5 True/False questions, with a +3 for a correct answer, a -2 for an incorrect answer, and a 0 for an unattempted question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curious marking scheme of this exam made one thing intuitively clear to both of us - if you don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer, making a guess &lt;em&gt;should be&lt;/em&gt; better than not attempting the question. And so Bose exclaimed, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;LMAO some students left the entire paper blank. They could have marked all the answers &amp;lsquo;True&amp;rsquo; and still have a fair chance of a positive score!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;But why all &amp;lsquo;True&amp;rsquo;? You could just mark all the answers according to your intuition and that should effectively be at least as good as random guessing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, I argued. Bose then asserted that random guessing may get you all your answers wrong, and the &amp;ldquo;all True / all False&amp;rdquo; method should be preferred. While Bose may have stated that impetuously, it &lt;abbr title=&#34;Koi sense hai is baat ki? Hame bohot lag rahi thi uss time. :p&#34;&gt;did get both of us thinking.&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My roommate Daljit gatecrashed the discussion and sided with Bose. However, after fiddling with pen and paper for some time, Bose yielded that &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;mathematically both the methods appear to have the same effect&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Obviously, the probability of getting all 5 answers incorrect in both the cases remains \( (0.5)^5 \).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now consider this: If you had to answer all the questions in a set of 5 True/False type questions, there are 32 possible ways you could do this. While calculating our probability of \( (0.5)^5 = 3.125\%\), we have assumed that all of these ways are equally likely to be the answer set that has all incorrect answers. Instinctively, this seems unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to set a question paper, I would try to maintain a balance between the number of True statements and the number of False statements. This idea is easier to visualize when there are more number of questions and more alternatives. Consider the JEE Main question paper : 90 questions, one correct option out of 4 alternatives (a), (b), (c) and (d). There is &lt;strong&gt;absolutely no way&lt;/strong&gt; (realistically) that the answer to all the questions be (a). In fact, it is expected that the number of questions with (a) as the correct answer would be roughly a quarter of the total number of questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when it comes to 5 True/False questions, it is not expected that all the answers be the same. And hence, marking all True / all False should have a better chance at not getting all the answers wrong, than randomly marking the answers. This needs a better mathematical analysis, but Bose got AIR 104 in JEE Advanced and so his advice regarding examinations should not be taken lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the marking scheme of the examination was such that would promote guessing. And this can be proven with some quick mathematics. Consider any examination where you have to select one out of \(N\) options. You get \(x\) points when you correctly answer a question, \(-y\) points when you incorrectly answer a question, and zero for not attempting the the question.
Thus, if you randonly guess an answer, the probabilty that you get it correct is \(\frac{1}{N}\). If you&amp;rsquo;re making a random guess for \(Q\) questions, then the total expected score due guessing would be :
$$
\begin{array}{r l}
 &amp;amp; Q[\frac{1}{N}x + (1-\frac{1}{N})(-y)] \\\&lt;br /&gt;
= &amp;amp; \frac{Q}{N}[x - (N-1)y]
\end{array}
$$
For an examination where random guessing should not make any difference, the expected score due to guessing should be equal to zero. With this condition, we can solve for \(y\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
\begin{array}{r c l}
\frac{Q}{N}[x - (N-1)y] &amp;amp; = &amp;amp; 0 \\\&lt;br /&gt;
x - (N-1)y &amp;amp; = &amp;amp; 0 \\\&lt;br /&gt;
\frac{x}{N-1} &amp;amp; = &amp;amp; y
\end{array}
$$
Therefore, in an ideal 1-out-of-N examination, the penalty for an incorrect answer should be \(-\frac{x}{N-1}\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To compare, Bose&amp;rsquo;s examination had a penatly of -2 instead of the ideal -3 (\(x=3, N=2\)), which implies that random guessing could leave one better off. JEE Main has a penalty of -1, but ideally it should have a penalty of -\(\frac{4}{3}\) (\(x=4, N=4\)). This is why I have always promoted guessing in JEE Main. I myself did that, and got a +7 in my score due to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a proponent of guessing, wherever the situation promotes it. And this comes in handy during quizzes. Almost all the time, you don&amp;rsquo;t know the exact answer for a question. It is all about working over the hints that the quizmaster subtly drops and making an educated guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when we went to participate in the Farida Abraham Memorial National Quiz in the La Martiniere Girls&amp;rsquo; College, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to any of the questions in the preliminary round. We still qualified for the finals just by making educated guesses. Ask any quizzer and they would recall a similar story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guesswork lies at the heart of quizzing. And it is the job of a good quizmaster to drop enough hints, and smart hints, such that the teams try to guess reasonable answers. Even if the answer is incorrect, a &amp;ldquo;good guess&amp;rdquo; from the quizmaster is a satisfactory consolation prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and we have made such progress on guessing that we have an entirely new field where computers are trained to guess &amp;ldquo;values&amp;rdquo;. Yes I&amp;rsquo;m talking about Machine Learning. This reminds me that I have to brush up my ML. Goodbye!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Machine Learning : Story #N&#43;1</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/learning-machine-learning-story-n-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 06:27:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/learning-machine-learning-story-n-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-m-achi-nist-dataset&#34;&gt;The M&lt;del&gt;ACHI&lt;/del&gt;NIST (dataset)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In November 2018, I was reading about neural networks, and the first hands-on example that the website had was to build a neural network to recognize handwritten numbers using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MNIST_database&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MNIST dataset&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
One month later, we had a lecture series on &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Machine Learning&amp;rdquo; in the winter camp of &lt;a href=&#34;http://pclub.in&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Programming Club, IITK&lt;/a&gt;. The MNIST dataset was again used to teach Neural Networks.&lt;br /&gt;
Now, the book that I&amp;rsquo;m following also has a section called &amp;ldquo;Hands-on Experience&amp;rdquo; in the very first chapter, which uses the MNIST dataset for handwritten character recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;doing-the-same-thing-again-and-again&#34;&gt;Doing the same thing, again and again.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-first-time-it-felt-like-magic&#34;&gt;The first time, it felt like magic.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what we were doing. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know why we were doing that. But it made my laptop start its fan, and apparently, the tests showed that the network had trained well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-second-time-i-was-still-clueless-though-a-little-bit-less-clueless&#34;&gt;The second time, I was still clueless. Though a little bit &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; clueless.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understood how the chosen error function translated to the update equations for the weights and biases. I knew what gradient descent was doing. I understood most of the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s and &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s, but the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; questions remained unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-third-time-i-got-overconfident&#34;&gt;The third time, I got overconfident.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now (somewhat) understood the implications of the choice of the error function. I also (somewhat) understood why the network was pyramidal in shape. I understood the benefits of one-hot encoding over label encoding. Overall, it felt like I knew what I was doing and why I was doing that. So now it was time for my own theories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;network-structure&#34;&gt;Network Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The network had 3 layers - the input layer, one hidden layer, and the output layer.&lt;br /&gt;
The images in the MNIST dataset are of size 28 x 28. Thus the input layer was of size 784. The hidden layer was chosen to be of size 100. And since we were using one-hot encoding, our output layer was of size 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, there were supposed to be two pairs of weights and biases - one for the transition from the input layer to the hidden layer, and one for the transition from the hidden layer to the output layer. So the first set of weights was a matrix of size 784x100, and the second was a matrix of size 100x10. The biases were simply arrays of sizes 100 and 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working&#34;&gt;Working&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;here-is-how-the-network-decides-the-digit-that-a-given-image-corresponds-to&#34;&gt;Here is how the network decides the digit that a given image corresponds to :&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After training, we have calculated the two pairs of weights and biases. We are given an image of size 28x28. This image corresponds to an array of 784 integers between 0 and 255. We take the product of this array (1 x 784) with the first weight matrix (784 x 100) to get an array of size 1 x 100. We add the values of the first bias array to this to get the intermediate answer array. We then take the product of the intermediate answer array (1 x 100) and the second weight matrix (100 x 10) to get an array of size 1 x 10.  Adding the second set of biases to this, we get the final answer array. Passing the values of this array to the softmax function, we obtain a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;score&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; between 0 and 1 for each digit. We then say that the given image corresponds to the digit with the highest score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-above-could-be-restated-in-english-as-follows&#34;&gt;The above could be restated in English as follows :&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the training process, we have obtained a set of 100 &lt;em&gt;patterns&lt;/em&gt; (first weight matrix), and we know that a particular digit has some subset of these patterns (second weight matrix). When we are given an image, in the first step, we calculate &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;to what extent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this image contains each of our 100 patterns. We then find the digit which has these patterns to a similar extent as the given image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, suppose we are given an image in which has one horizontal line in the upper part of the image and one vertical line in the right portion. We realize that these patterns most closely correspond to the digit 7 and declare that this image has 7 written in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-experiment&#34;&gt;The Experiment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the mathematical description of the model is explicit regarding the rules that determine the digit corresponding to an image, the English version has a rather mystical element to it, and this makes the latter more intriguing. As an attempt to demystify it, I tried to visualize the &lt;em&gt;patterns&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The patterns are represented by the first weight matrix, which is of size 784 x 100. We could consider this matrix as 100 arrays of size 784 - with each array representing a pattern (a 28x28 image). I wrote a simple python program to convert an array of size 784 to a 28x28 image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/dryairship/f5ae3c76a679542d6981334faef98bb3.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;epic-fail&#34;&gt;Epic Fail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-is-what-i-expected-the-patterns-to-look-like&#34;&gt;This is what I expected the patterns to look like:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;patterns-expected.png&#34; alt=&#34;Expected Patterns&#34; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Expected Patterns (shown 6 out of &amp;lt;indeterminate&amp;gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A curve in the top right corner is a feature of the digits 2, 3, 8, 9 and 0. A horizontal line in the upper part is a feature of the digit 7. A curve in the bottom left corner is a feature of the digits 5, 6, 8 and 0. A vertical line is a feature of the digits 1, 4 and 7. I anticipated that the patterns obtained from the weight matrix would look somewhat like these, but was utterly disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-is-what-the-patterns-actually-looked-like&#34;&gt;This is what the patterns actually looked like:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;patterns-actual.png&#34; alt=&#34;Actual Patterns&#34; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Actual Patterns (shown 6 out of 100)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noise!&lt;/strong&gt; That&amp;rsquo;s noise! Those images do not seem to have any pattern at all! But believe it or not, this is how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of the experiment was completely contrary to what I was hoping for. However, a sober reconsideration of the idea of the experiment would drop hints that the experiment was destined to fail :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had completely disregarded the importance of the bias array and the entire experiment was based solely on the first weight matrix.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had fallen prey to the fallacy that a computer would &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; exactly the way humans do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so with a failed experiment, I decided that I was done with ML for the day, or maybe for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dryairship : Origins</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/dryairship-origins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 01:53:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/dryairship-origins/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is a collection of the answers to the most frequent questions I am asked about my username.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-dryairship-mean&#34;&gt;What does dryairship mean?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It literally means &lt;a href=&#34;https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/dry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Airship&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;airship&lt;/a&gt;. You could always break it down as dry-airship or dry-air-ship as per your own will, and then iterate over the various meanings of the words &lt;strong&gt;dry&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;air&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;ship&lt;/strong&gt; to let it mean whatever pleases you. I, however, like to visualize it as a cute &lt;em&gt;non-moist&lt;/em&gt; airship floating in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Source: https://myrealdomain.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cartoon-blimp-original.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only other allusion that dryairship incorporates, is that it happens to be an anagram of my legal first name &lt;strong&gt;Priydarshi&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-i-think-of-dryairship&#34;&gt;How did I think of dryairship?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;td;dr&lt;/strong&gt; : I didn&amp;rsquo;t. I wrote a program to find it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before coming to IITK, I realized I needed a nice username for all my online accounts. Also somewhat around that time, I had finished the entire Harry Potter movie series. I was particularly impressed by the scene in which &amp;ldquo;Tom Marvolo Riddle&amp;rdquo; was permutated to &amp;ldquo;I am Lord Voldemort&amp;rdquo;. Further, I read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/How-was-the-anagram-Tom-Marvolo-Riddle-to-I-am-Lord-Voldemort-translated-into-other-languages-in-Harry-Potter-versions-around-the-world&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;how this scene was performed in other languages&lt;/a&gt; and also found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/harrypotter/comments/vm2d2/xpost_from_rfunny/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a reddit post that has other anagrams for Tom Marvolo Riddle&lt;/a&gt;. And then it was decided - I needed a username that was an anagram of my name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dryairship/meaningful-anagrams&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;simple Java program&lt;/a&gt; to find meaningful anagrams of my name. (&lt;em&gt;Note: Although it seems as if the program would take factorial time, it runs in polynomial time.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the output of the program, I zeroed in on dryairship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;of-all-the-907200-permutations-why-dryairship&#34;&gt;Of all the 907200 permutations, why dryairship?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because dryairship is better than &lt;code&gt;hairy drips&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;his dry pair&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;air dry hips&lt;/code&gt; or any other anagram. I did linger over &lt;code&gt;sir hardy pi&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sir pi hydra&lt;/code&gt; for a few minutes but then decided against using the title &lt;code&gt;sir&lt;/code&gt; in my username.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-dryairship-related-to-aerospace-engineering&#34;&gt;Is dryairship related to Aerospace Engineering?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not intentionally. Though the fact that I was about to join IITK to study Aerospace Engineering could have been an implicit factor in making me choose dryairship over other alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-would-happen-if-the-airship-becomes-wet&#34;&gt;What would happen if the airship becomes wet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve only completed one course of Aerospace Engineering as of writing of this post and find myself incapable of describing what effects the wetness of the surface of the airship would have on the flight. The answer to this question would be updated as soon as I do a course which teaches me that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More questions, as their frequency increases, would be added here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Machine Learning : Story #N</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/learning-machine-learning-story-n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 17:38:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/learning-machine-learning-story-n/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This series is based on my attempts at exploring machine learning, and the final results of those attempts. It starts straightaway with part N because I do not remember how many times I have tried to do this before, only to leave it for the future. Just as a side note, I&amp;rsquo;m not completely illiterate at ML. However, my proficiency, as of writing this post, is limited to linear regression, which some of my friends do sometimes regard as complete illiteracy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the endsems are over and my unremitting self is again motivated to proclaim &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll learn ML in these vacations&amp;rdquo;. Having tried my hands at all sorts of online resources, this time I decide to use a physical book as my guide. So I go to the library and pick up this book titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Machine-Learning-Constraint-Based-Marco-Ph-D/dp/0081006594&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Machine Learning: A constraint-based approach&lt;/a&gt; by Professor Marco Gori.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is 2 AM, I&amp;rsquo;m on chapter one, and the current topic is why Euclidean distance is not a good metric in higher dimensions. So we&amp;rsquo;re working in the n-dimensional set \( \mathbb{X} \) and the author defines the set of neighbours of a point \(x_{0}\) as :
$$ \mathcal{N}_R (x_{0}) = \{ x \in \mathbb{X}\,\, |\,\, ||x-x_{0}|| &amp;lt; R\}$$
where \(R\) is the degree of neighbourhood of \(x_{0}\) (i.e., the radius). We call this the orange. He then brings up the formula for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Volume_of_an_n-ball&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;volume of an n-ball&lt;/a&gt; (which I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen before) :
&lt;a title=&#34;Volume of an n-ball&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Volume of an n-ball&#34; style=&#34;filter: invert(1); -webkit-filter: invert(1);&#34; src=&#34;https://wikimedia.org/api/rest_v1/media/math/render/svg/4247a3f5a3cc59a2dc1b08af20ec7a210db1ca06&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
where \(n\) is the number of dimensions, \(R\) is the radius of the ball, and \(\Gamma\) is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamma_function&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gamma function&lt;/a&gt;.
Trusting the author without verifying the veracity of the formula (as I&amp;rsquo;ve always done), I move on to the definiton of the peel of this orange. We define \(\epsilon &amp;gt; 0\) as the thickness of the peel, which we denote as \(\mathcal{P}_{\epsilon}\). The radius of the pulp, therefore, reduces to \(R-\epsilon\). The volume of the peel is then obtained by subtracting the volume of the pulp from the volume of the orange.
$$
\begin{align}
vol(\mathcal{P}_{\epsilon}) &amp;amp;= vol(\mathcal{N}_R) - vol(\mathcal{N}_{R-\epsilon})\\\&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;amp;= vol(\mathcal{N}_R) \left(1 - \frac{vol(\mathcal{N}_{R-\epsilon})}{vol(\mathcal{N}_R)}\right)\\\&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;amp;= vol(\mathcal{N}_R) \left(1 - \left(\frac{R-\epsilon}{R}\right)^{n}\right)
\end{align}
$$
Now we let the dimensions increase. Formally, we let \(n \to \infty\).
$$
\begin{align}
vol(\mathcal{P}_{\epsilon}) &amp;amp;= vol(\mathcal{N}_R) \left(1 - \lim \limits_{n \to \infty} \left(\frac{R-\epsilon}{R}\right)^{n}\right)
\end{align}
$$
Since \(R-\epsilon &amp;lt; R\), we have \(\frac{R-\epsilon}{R}&amp;lt;1\) which implies \( \lim \limits_{n \to \infty} \left(\frac{R-\epsilon}{R}\right)^{n}\ = 0\).
Thus, we get
$$
vol(\mathcal{P}_{\epsilon}) = vol(\mathcal{N}_R)
$$
 and the orange becomes its peel. This is it. This blows my mind. I naively declare this as the pinnacle of mathematical beauty that has ever been unleashed to me, and go to bed, thinking about all the jokes I could make with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I even bother to check the proof of the formula for the volume of the n-ball? No. I merely verified that it holds for 1, 2 and 3 dimensions. But what if there is some catch in higher dimensions, I wonder as I lie down on my bed. I then lazily conclude that the author must have checked the proof before writing the formula in his book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were we discussing about how Euclidean metrics fail in higher dimensions? No. We were discussing about a greedy orange-loving alien who has invented a dimension-changinator and would be wanting to increase the number of dimensions of his orange, and how he would be disappointed to get only the peel if he increases the number of dimensions to very large values.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralized Inventory and Purchasing</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/project/centralized-inventory-and-purchasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 03:28:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/project/centralized-inventory-and-purchasing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Flight Stalled</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-first-flight-stalled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 03:44:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-first-flight-stalled/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-title-is-a-clickbait&#34;&gt;The title is a clickbait&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not exactly, hehe.&lt;br /&gt;
 ✔️   It was my first flight.&lt;br /&gt;
 ✔️   The flight stalled.&lt;br /&gt;
 ✔️   I was scared.&lt;br /&gt;
 ❌   I thought I was going to die.&lt;br /&gt;
The stall was a planned one, you see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aerospace-is-the-coooooolest-department&#34;&gt;Aerospace is the coooooolest department&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 3rd semester, AE students have the course AE201 - Introduction to Aerospace Engineering. This course is aimed at introducing us to the basic principles of flight.&lt;br /&gt;
As a part of the course, we had visits to the various labs of the department (wind tunnel, flight laboratory, etc) and a demo flight in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iitk.ac.in/aero/fltlab/cessna.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cessna Skylane&lt;/a&gt;. The flight was supposed to be a demonstration of the various maneuvers that a pilot can perform to control the six degrees of freedom of an aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;physics-of-stall&#34;&gt;Physics of stall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An aircraft can stall in two ways :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angle_of_attack&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;angle of attack&lt;/a&gt; increases beyond the critical angle of attack.&lt;/strong&gt; So you have an aircraft in a steady-level flight, and you increase the angle between the wings and the incoming wind (eg: by pointing the aircraft upwards). You get more lift. You like it, so you increase the angle further. You get even more lift. You think this is good business, so you keep increasing the angle until you reach the angle where your lift suddenly starts decreasing. This is the critical angle of attack.
&lt;a title=&#34;botag. [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons&#34; href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Lift_curve.svg&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;512&#34; alt=&#34;Lift curve&#34; style=&#34;background-color:white;&#34; src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d1/Lift_curve.svg/512px-Lift_curve.svg.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The speed of the aircraft falls below the stall speed.&lt;/strong&gt; At a given altitude, there is a minimum speed (stall speed) that the aircraft must have in order to generate enough lift to maintain that altitude. If the speed of the aircraft drops below the stall speed, the aircraft starts, well, &lt;em&gt;falling down&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our case, the pilot probably paused or slowed down the engine so that the speed of the aircraft dropped below the stall speed. Of course, the pilot was able to regain control over the aircraft and the fall was immediately followed by a pull-up maneuver so we could feel the extra G-force. The pilot then performed various other maneuvers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iitk-from-above&#34;&gt;IITK from above&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun surveying the campus from the Skylane. I made a video of the entire ride. In the snapshot below you can see Halls 13,12,11,10,9&amp;hellip;, Hockey and Football ground, OAT, Swimming Pool, Pronite ground, RA/SBRA buildings, GHT, Main stadium, etc. Apologies for the blurry image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;iitk-from-above.png&#34; alt=&#34;IITK From Above&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Extracted Hidden Test Cases In Google FooBar</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/how-i-extracted-hidden-test-cases-in-google-foobar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 12:30:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/how-i-extracted-hidden-test-cases-in-google-foobar/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hey there! In my &lt;a href=&#34;https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-google-foobar-experience/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about my Google FooBar experience. I recommend you to read that post before you continue with this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will explain how I managed to extract hidden test cases from Google FooBar. Note that I had reported the bug through the &lt;code&gt;feedback&lt;/code&gt; command via the &lt;em&gt;FooBar terminal&lt;/em&gt;. Although I did not receive any response from Google for that report, this flaw has now been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-mild-confusion&#34;&gt;A mild confusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered an important fact about FooBar&amp;rsquo;s test case evaluations when I was solving the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; problem of the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; level. Upon finally completing the code for the solution, I used the &lt;code&gt;verify&lt;/code&gt; command to check it. To my dismay, only the first test case passed. I went through my solution again to find any logical errors, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any. In my opinion, the program should have worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had already discovered that the first two test cases on which my solution was evaluated were the same as the ones given in the examples. And I had verified that my solution worked for the two example cases before I submitted the code. That was weird. At least the first two cases should have passed! Nevertheless, I decided to test the program on the example cases once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bluej-3&#34;&gt;BlueJ &amp;lt;3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that fact that I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bluej.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BlueJ&lt;/a&gt; (it&amp;rsquo;s an awesome Java IDE, BTW) was instrumental in helping me unravel the mystery. BlueJ has the option of calling static functions of a class through a popup menu obtained by right clicking the name of the class. This opens a dialog box that asks for the parameters to be passed to the function.
&lt;img src=&#34;bluej_call.png&#34; alt=&#34;BlueJ Method Call&#34; /&gt;
When the function completes its execution, another dialog box pops up which contains the return value of the function.
&lt;img src=&#34;bluej_return.png&#34; alt=&#34;BlueJ Method Return&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-same-mild-confusion-now-17-extra-for-free&#34;&gt;The same mild confusion, now 17% extra for free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I recompiled the &lt;strong&gt;same&lt;/strong&gt; program (&lt;em&gt;not a very sane idea, I know, but wait&lt;/em&gt;) and called the &lt;code&gt;answer&lt;/code&gt; function directly from BlueJ&amp;rsquo;s fantastic UI, with the input being the first example test case (&lt;em&gt;yes, the one that was already giving me the correct answer on FooBar&amp;rsquo;s evaluation - not a very sane idea again, but wait&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell you, in this world, being a little crazy helps to keep you sane.  - Zsa Zsa Gabor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; as the output, which was the correct answer. Then, I again called the &lt;code&gt;answer&lt;/code&gt; function with the input being the second example test case. (&lt;em&gt;Note: No recompiling. I just closed the output window of the first example, and called the function again.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boom!&lt;/strong&gt; This time, I got &lt;code&gt;7&lt;/code&gt; as the output. The correct answer was supposed to be &lt;code&gt;6&lt;/code&gt;. That was funny. I remember I got &lt;code&gt;6&lt;/code&gt; as the output the last time I passed the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; parameters to the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; code. Just to confirm it, I recompiled the code, called the function with the second example case, and found the output to be &lt;code&gt;6&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;puzzle-solved&#34;&gt;Puzzle solved!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment, I knew that my code was correct. It was Java that was acting weirdly, or so I tended to believe. I was almost ready to post this as a question on StackOverflow, when I decided to look at my code again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And here comes the big moment&lt;/em&gt;. I realized that the value that the &lt;code&gt;answer&lt;/code&gt; function was supposed to return, was stored in a &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; variable. (&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t judge me. I have now learnt that it is a bad practice.&lt;/em&gt;) Thus, the variable was conserved across multiple calls of the &lt;code&gt;answer&lt;/code&gt; function on the same instance of the Java Virtual Machine. And I had never explicitly set the variable to 0. I just kept on increasing the value of the variable (in another static function - which did the calculations), and returned it when the calculations were over. Thus, when I called the function the second time, the variable still contained its previous value. Hence, I got &lt;code&gt;7&lt;/code&gt; = &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;code&gt;6&lt;/code&gt; as my answer for the second test case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recompiling a program in BlueJ resets the Java Virtual Machine. Hence, the static variables are restored to their initial values. This is why I got the correct answer when I ran the program after recompiling it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I solved the issue by simply putting a statement to reset the variable to 0 before performing the calculations. With this modification, my program passed all the test cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important fact that I learnt here is that Google was calling the &lt;code&gt;answer&lt;/code&gt; function on the same instance of JVM for all the test cases.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;em&gt;So is this a flaw?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Yes!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Can we exploit it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a flaw if we couldn&amp;rsquo;t exploit it!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lost-in-a-maze&#34;&gt;Lost in a maze&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; problem of level 3, I had to find the length of the shortest path from the bottom-right corner to the top-left corner of a boolean matrix. &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt; represented a block where we could move, and &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; represented a piece of wall. Also, I was allowed to remove at most one wall from the maze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about BFS/DFS back then. &lt;em&gt;(I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about any standard algorithms, in fact. :&amp;lsquo;( )&lt;/em&gt;  As a result, I coded up a very &lt;em&gt;dirty&lt;/em&gt; solution (must&amp;rsquo;ve been DFS, only I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it was called so). And it worked. Well, &lt;strong&gt;almost&lt;/strong&gt;! It passed &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; test cases.
&lt;img src=&#34;test4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Test Case 4&#34; /&gt;
I tried hard to find a bug or an edge case that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t considered, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. So I decided to find an altogether different approach to solve the problem. While thinking of a better solution to the problem, an evil idea struck me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-want-to-hack-nasa-sup-google-sup-with-html-sup-binary-code-sup&#34;&gt;I want to hack &lt;del&gt;NASA&lt;/del&gt; &lt;sup&gt;Google&lt;/sup&gt; with &lt;del&gt;HTML&lt;/del&gt; &lt;sup&gt;Binary Code&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that the JVM was the same across evaluations implied that I could share data among different runs of the program. So I did two things :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a static variable named &lt;code&gt;testCase&lt;/code&gt; that is incremented every time the &lt;code&gt;answer&lt;/code&gt; function is called. This will contain the serial number of the test case that is being currently evaluated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store the data of the current test case into other static variables. This could be :

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a single variable - in which case the data of one test case will be available only to the next test case, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an array - in which case the data of one test case will be available to all subsequent test cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so now I have the data of the previous test case stored in a static variable.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do I use it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;By failing on purpose!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to succeed, double your failure rate. - Thomas Watson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;idea&#34;&gt;Idea&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convert the data of the previous test case into binary form. If the number at the &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;th position is &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;, run the program as it is supposed to. If it is &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;, return a garbage value so that the current test case fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;implementation&#34;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stored the matrix of the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; test case in a static variable. When inside the 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; test case evaluation, I used the above mentioned idea to return the correct/incorrect output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first converted the length of the matrix to a binary string and checked for the character at index &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; (I had to manually increment the value of &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; after every submission). If this bit was &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;, I returned &lt;code&gt;-1&lt;/code&gt;, otherwise I let the program run as it was supposed to. On observing the results, if only the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; test case failed, the inference drawn was that the bit at &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;th index was 1. If both the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and the 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; test cases failed, the inference drawn was that the bit at &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;th index was 0. When the index grew bigger than the length of the binary string, a Runtime Error was thrown instead of a Wrong Answer. This way, I found the binary representation of the length of the matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I repeated the process for the breadth, and then for the entire matrix (&lt;em&gt;except, I didn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-far-more-unheroic-but-faster-way&#34;&gt;A far more unheroic, but faster way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had found out almost half the matrix when I realized that instead of obtaining the entire matrix, I could just guess the answer. Since I had to find the length of shortest path, the answer would satisfy:
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;code&gt;length+breadth-1 &amp;lt;= answer &amp;lt; length*breadth&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(much less than &lt;code&gt;length*breadth&lt;/code&gt; actually)
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for all the test cases, I would let the program run normally, while for the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; test case, I would return a custom value. I started with &lt;code&gt;length+breadth-1&lt;/code&gt;, and kept incrementing it until the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; test case passed too. (&lt;em&gt;Okay fine, a very despicable way to pass a test case, indeed. This is probably why I didn&amp;rsquo;t whine when I didn&amp;rsquo;t hear from Google - I hadn&amp;rsquo;t completely solved this problem.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The binary conversion method, although a long procedure, could be successfully used to extract hidden test cases from Google FooBar - much more easily for problems which have a few &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; values as the input. &lt;strong&gt;However, it requires that at least one test case succeeding the failing test case, must pass&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although finding hidden test cases isn&amp;rsquo;t that much of a benefit (as it&amp;rsquo;ll only help if the program fails for some edge cases), they are &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo; for a reason, and it would be better if they remain so! I&amp;rsquo;m glad that Google has now fixed the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Google FooBar Experience</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-google-foobar-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 23:00:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/my-google-foobar-experience/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hey all! This blog post is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://foobar.withgoogle.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google FooBar&lt;/a&gt;, how I got invited to it, the problems, and what happened at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;invitation&#34;&gt;Invitation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legend has it that Google FooBar is Google’s &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;secret hiring challenge&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. You can take part in it only if you have an invitation and you if you perform well enough you may be hired! I am aware of two ways one can get an invitation :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Search -&lt;/strong&gt; Apparently, making enough programming related searches on Google can get you an invitation (as was the case with me). I have no idea regarding the algorithm which decides if you have made &lt;em&gt;enough&lt;/em&gt; searches. I have been searching for solutions to programming problems since 2012 (okay, those searches must have been quite silly), and it was only in January 2017 that I got the invitation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referral -&lt;/strong&gt; People who have completed some challenges on FooBar get a URL which they can share with their friends to invite them to participate. Again, I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many challenges one needs to solve to get the referral link. I got mine when FooBar resumed after being down for extended maintenance for about a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interface&#34;&gt;Interface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After logging in, one is greeted with a linux-terminal like screen. &lt;code&gt;help&lt;/code&gt; lists out the various commands that work in this terminal.
&lt;img src=&#34;commands.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google FooBar Commands&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;request&lt;/code&gt; creates a new directory which contains the problem statement and the solution templates. The solutions can be in either &lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;python&lt;/strong&gt;. One can only have a single active challenge at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time I was invited for the challenge, Java was, sort-of, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/search?tab=votes&amp;amp;q=user%3a4121347%20%5bjava%5d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my mother tongue&lt;/a&gt; :p. So I submitted my solutions in Java. The Java template for each problem had a function like this, which we were supposed to complete :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Java&#34;&gt;public static int answer(&amp;lt;params&amp;gt;) {
    ...
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;problems&#34;&gt;Problems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems were like regular &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Competitive_programming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CP&lt;/a&gt; problems. Most of them were solvable by using &lt;strong&gt;dynamic programming&lt;/strong&gt;. However, at that time, I was a novice at CP and completely inexperienced at dynamic programming, and hence solving every problem was a matter of extreme pride and happiness for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems were divided into 5 levels :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 1 had 1 problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 2 had 2 problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 3 had 3 problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 4 again had 2 problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 5 supposedly had only 1 problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to sail through the first four levels easily (except problem 2 of level 3 - explained in &lt;a href=&#34;https://dryairship.github.io/post/how-i-extracted-hidden-test-cases-in-google-foobar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;), but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t complete the challenge as I failed to solve the only problem of the 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had 25 days to solve the last problem, and I spent the first 10 days without much worry - I was doltishly expecting this one to be of the same difficulty level as the previous ones, which were surprisingly quite simple. As it turned out, I was very wrong. I came up with a few different ways to solve the problem, but all my solutions were essentially brute-force (with a time complexity  of O(2&lt;sup&gt;mn&lt;/sup&gt;)) and were naturally taking a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I lost all hopes of solving the problem on my own, I posted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/q/41923054/4121347&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;question on StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;, and even put a bounty on it! However, I failed to get an answer (the question has no accepted answer even today, because apparently the problem was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cellular_automaton&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cellular Automation&lt;/a&gt; problem, and my naive approach was very different from the expected solution).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;status&lt;/code&gt; commands prints the progress of a user. For me, the output is like this :
&lt;img src=&#34;status.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google FooBar Status&#34; /&gt;
When I cleared the third level, Google gave me an option to use the &lt;code&gt;recruitme&lt;/code&gt; command, which supposedly shared my progress with a Google recruiter. I decided to use it at the end of the challenge. Later, since I couldn&amp;rsquo;t solve the last problem, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really expect anyone from Google to contact me. Still, hoping for the best, I used the command, and entered the information it asked - like name, contact details, education etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard from any Google recruiter. Perhaps because I was still in school then - they asked this when I entered the details. Or maybe because I cheated on the 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; problem of the 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; level (read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dryairship.github.io/post/how-i-extracted-hidden-test-cases-in-google-foobar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; for details). Or perhaps because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t solve the last problem. Or maybe because Google stopped hiring through FooBar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reason may be, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really disappointed. Solving those problems gave me immense confidence and the inspiration to perform better at the next opportunity I get. And of course, the invitation for Google FooBar is in itself a procurement to cherish!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meow, World!</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/post/meow-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 23:33:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/post/meow-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there, everyone! I am Priydarshi and this is my blog. Here I would be posting primarily programming related stuff, in addition to my experiences at IITK and in general life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was the motivation for me to start this blog?&lt;br /&gt;
1. Almost all of the cool seniors I know have their own blogs.&lt;br /&gt;
2. I believe I have stories to tell, and knowledge to share.&lt;br /&gt;
3. I wanted to tick off another item from my bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final examinations for the second semester ended yesterday and so now I finally have the time to try my hand at maintaining a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently this blog is hosted on GitHub Pages (&lt;em&gt;though I might later shift it to a personal domain&lt;/em&gt;). I am using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt; theme and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; framework for maintaining this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Hugo claims to be user-friendly, my experience with setting up this blog wasn&amp;rsquo;t as smooth as I expected it to be. So I find &lt;code&gt;apt&lt;/code&gt; to be easiest way to install any package. But apparently, &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install hugo&lt;/code&gt; installs an older version of Hugo, and on trying to build this site with that version, I ended up with an error message telling me that the Academic theme isn&amp;rsquo;t compatible with my current Hugo version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Current theme does not support Hugo version 0.40.1. Minimum version required is 0.54
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I purged the &lt;code&gt;apt&lt;/code&gt; version. What, then, is the next easiest way to install a package? &lt;code&gt;snap&lt;/code&gt;! So I did &lt;code&gt;sudo snap install hugo&lt;/code&gt;. Trying to build the site with this gave me another scary error message :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;failed to transform resource: TOCSS: failed to transform &amp;quot;scss/main.scss&amp;quot; (text/x-scss): this feature is not available in your current Hugo version, see https://goo.gl/YMrWcn for more information.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some unknown reason, I chose to ignore the link in the error message and decided to Google the error. I found the same error on StackOverflow (&lt;em&gt;The real happiness? +_+&lt;/em&gt;) and the accepted answer recommended me to install the tarball version of Hugo. So I did that, but ended up with the same error message. (&lt;em&gt;What can be more sad than an accepted SO answer not helping you out?&lt;/em&gt; ;_; )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I decided to follow the link in the error message, and found a very easy &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/troubleshooting/faq/#i-get-tocss-this-feature-is-not-available-in-your-current-hugo-version&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;solution&lt;/a&gt; to this error - apparently I had installed the normal version, whereas I needed the &lt;code&gt;extended&lt;/code&gt; version. (&lt;em&gt;*facepalm*&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learnt : &lt;strong&gt;An error message doesn&amp;rsquo;t always come with a link to its solution. So when it does, follow the link blindly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my first blog post. Hope you stick around to read my future posts!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Election Manager</title>
      <link>https://dryairship.github.io/project/online-election-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 19:32:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dryairship.github.io/project/online-election-manager/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
